SUMMARY

Searching for a job in IT, be it remote or onsite (lasi, Romania).

Please do not contact me for opportunities that require skills that I do not own, nor for ones that require less skills/expertise than I currently have.

Eighteen year old with 22yr experience in *nix based systems.

Perl, bash, sed, awk, make, cmake, some ansi c, some php, some python, kernel hacking, embedded dev (mips, arm, atmel/arduino).

Networking experience: Mikrotik, Cisco L2-3, Juniper, bgp, ospf, rip, IpSec, multihoming. Virtualization: OpenVZ, Xen, Kvm, Qemu, VmWare, VirtualBox, FreeBSD containers, Ixc, docker

EXPERIENCES

Sr DevOPS Engineer and Team Lead (JACK OF ALL TRADES)

October 2013 - current

eZLO

Caring for clusters (k8s, docker), servers, virtual machines, alongside firmware integration, packaging (deb/rpm), analytics (ELK)

Lead for:

- · devops/sysadmins
- firmware integration team (2014-2020)
- analytics (ELK) (2016-2020)

Activities:

Infrastructure design and deployment in AWS, GKE, DigitalOcean, Hetzner, Oracle, Azure or hybrid environments.

Automating cloud components build and deploy for k8s, docker, lxc/lxd or VM's with all the things in place:

- databases (including replication, sharding)
- NFS mounts, CEPH, iSCSI, glusterFS etc
- · networking with multiple zones, firewall, routing rules, BGP, IPsec

Automation and management of:

- Gitlab
- Jenkins
- Rundeck

Writing IaC - Helm, Terraform, Puppet, Ansible

Maintenance of the server fleet (roughly 200-ish physical servers, VM's, AWS/EC2 or GCP hosts)

Package maintainer for our own internal software - Debian, RedHAT

Package maintainer for mips/arm (openwrt based)

Backporting libraries for OpenWRT apps (c/c++)

Porting packages for OpenWRT

Porting our solution to Intel Quark (Galileo)

Maintaining internal apps and tools

 $\label{lem:maintaing} \mbox{ analytics platform(s) and gathering of data, alongside other colleagues}$

Database monitoring, performance tweaking and configuration (mysql, posgresql)

Writing scripts for SysV init, OpenRC, systemd, Monit, Nagios and others

Office networking - pfSense, OPNSense, Cisco, Mikrotik, Juniper, VLANs



Alex Negulescu

Sr DevOPS, SmartHome/IoT & Networking

■ alecs+filtered@negulescu.me (mailto: alecs+filtered@negulescu.me)

-----g----g

alecs.github.io (http://alecs.github.io)

in linkedin.com/in/alecsey (https://in.linkedin.com/in/alecsey)

github.com/alecs (http://github.com/alecs)

y @antis0cialul (https://twitter.com/@antis0cialul)

cv.pdf (http://alecs.github.io/cv.pdf)

EDUCATION

Engineer's degree (NO LICENSE)

"Gheorghe Asachi" Technical University, Iasi 2011 - 2015

"Technologies and telecommunications systems"

High school

"Gheorghe Airinei" Technical College, Bucharest 1999 - 2003

Telecom electronist

LANGUAGES

Romanian (Native)

English (Fluent)

Spanish (Advanced)

French (Basic)

Perl programmer

Mind CTI

August 2012 - Oct 2013

Developing plugins/modules for the Nagios monitoring system, with Perl and C, both server part and client part (nsclient++/nrpe)

Create web interfaces with Perl

Patch internal scrips done by other colleagues or for OSS that Mind uses Develop patches for ticketing system based on Otrs and maintain Oracle database

Name and address of employer: Mind CTI, Ciurchi 126-128, Iaşi, Romania

Sysadmin

June 2005 - August 2010

XCT.RO ONLINE

Management of servers and network Software/hardware testing

Website developer - php, Perl, MySQL/PgSQL + wpress/textpattern/osCommerce Installing and configuring servers and workstations, switches and routers Maintaining the network for a small ISP with ±100 customers

Name and address of employer: SC HOL.RO SRL, C-tin Rădulescu Motru 25, 4rd district, Bucharest

⟨→ INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS

helm-charts (https://github.com/SysOPSRO/helm-charts)

Personal charts.charts.sysops.ro/) I use for work and other projetcs. Right now it's only one package, busybox-httpd, which I specifically use to deliver the CA cert for K8s clusters deployed with the digitalocean-cluster-setup mentioned below.

digitalocean-cluster-setup (https://github.com/SysOPSRO/digitalocean-cluster-setup)

Needed an easy way to add RBAC (auth) to an existing k8s DigitalOcean cluster by bundling some open source tools into a simple to deploy helm repo.

legacy-cloud-to-docker ()

eZLO LTD

Backported to docker with Alpine an app that required to be built and ran on Ubuntu 12.04 or Debian Jessie.

Managed to make it build in 4 steps via Gitlab CI and then run in docker or podman, using nginx as a reverse proxy.

encrypted-firmware-retrieval ()

eZLO LTD

We needed to have a method to deliver embedded device firmware through a secured (or not) connection, but having the datastream protected in a dynamic way, so that every device downloading the firmware will be downloading different content, decrypting it locally after the download.

encrypted-backup ()

eZLO LTD

Created an algorithm to encrypt the backup containing the critical files stored on an embedded device.

getPermissions ()

eZLO LTD

Created an AWK script that was used to decode a base64 string and parse the encapsulated json, checking for certain variables and settings stored in the object.

OnCall manager ()

INTERESTS

writing code
home automation
embeded devices
traveling
eating
making burgers

RELATED COURSES

BrainBench Courses

Took LinkedIn's implementation of oncall and adapted it so it supports authenticating against database stored users. Created a roster managing script that fills the database per team needs.

Code will be pushed online eventually.

motionpie (https://github.com/alecs/motionpie)

2015 - 2016

Ported the stack for Banana M3 PRO. Initially it was only working on Raspberry PI, and I only had BananaPI's. I had to use a different kernel and also adapt some build parameters. I also updated some packages that were installed by default.

fup.sh (https://github.com/alecs/fupsh)

2011-2013

While having a smallish ISP, the users were connecting through PPtP, and we needed a way of fairly sharing the outbound bandwidth between users.

There were also other methods, like using a VM and apply QoS on the traffic through it, but this was good enough at the time.

smokeping-plugins (https://github.com/alecs/smokeping-plugins)

I was in need of a plugin that was small and fast and could run on a small monitoring system that I already had. So I created a minimal Perl plugin, that works with smokeping; the plugin monitors the current latency of a MySQL server.

■ GROUP PROJECTS

Private datacenter cloud (Orange France) ()

eZLO LTD

Designed the architecture to run our solution in a private cloud, via virtual machines running Red Hat Linux on VMWare nodes.

Lead all the aspects related to the project: meetings, design, porting from Ubtunu to Red Hat, installation, setup monitoring (passive and active).

AWS SmartHome Cloud w private mobile APN in AT&T ()

eZLO LTD

Our client was manufacturing and selling an alarm panel, with no WiFi capability - only 3g/4g SIM. We had to make a setup that was secure and accomodated client requests. The SIM was provisioned in a different APN, with no access to DNS or any external service; it was only allowed to access specific IP addresses (which were private)

trudesk-fork (https://github.com/SysOPSRO/trudesk)

Needed an easy to manage service desk like alternative, since the team was big at that time

Took the open source truedesk, adapted it to docker initially **per this comment**(https://github.com/polonel/trudesk/issues/326#issuecomment-760354190) and then also did a patch to have mobile UI working.

Have some other patches that were not published yet, including requirement to have tags to create a ticket, helm(k8s) deployment, nginx delivery of static content - ie only /api/ is delivered by trudesk itself.

i-MSCP (https://github.com/SysOPSRO/imscp)

OSS Hosting control panel, to which I contributed a few minor changes.

aws-elk-billing (https://github.com/SysOPSRO/aws-elk-billing)

Tools for Loading and Visualizing GCP and AWS Detailed Billing with ELK(Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana)

Analytics ()

eZLO LTD

Gathering data from out cloud platforms, to be able to display metrics of the most important aspects of the business.

Logs download interface (for customer care) ()

eZLO LTD

Using OSS, created a protected web portal to help customer care download logs from the client owned devices, so they help the client (and development team) debug any issues.

₹ SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

QEMU XEN Proxmox OpenVZ LXC Docker Kubernetes k3s podman

MySQL Administration PgSQL Administration LAMP management Perl BASH

ANSI C Networking (IPv4) CISCO L2/L3 JunOS Mikrotik iptables FreeBSD PF

pfSense OpnSense IpCOP OpenVPN IPsec WireGuard Terraform helm

P HONORS & AWARDS

Oracle DBA 2013 Mind CTI

▶ VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

OpenSuse OBS Packager lasi, Romania	2020 - current
TUIASI Network Admin Iasi, Romania	2010 - 2013
LTV lasi CS Competition lasi, Romania	2011 - 2012
ALT Linux packaging team lasi, Romania	2009 - 2013

Last update: 11-Jul-24

© 2019-2024 Alex Negulescu